Finding Aid for Denison family papers, 1848-1907
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Denison family papers 1848-1907
Denison family
1 linear foot
85129 Aa 2
Grand Rapids, Michigan, family. Correspondence and business and legal papers of Julius Coe Denison; diaries, 1886-1890 and 1897-1907, of Julius' wife, Cornelia Carter Denison, describing daily life; and diaries, 1879-1889, of their son, Arthur Carter Denison, concerning in part his activities as student at the University of Michigan in the 1880s.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mrs. Paul F. Kempter (donor no. 6998 )
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Julius Coe Denison was born in New York and moved to Grand Rapids in 1855 where he was involved in agricultural and real estate activities. He and his wife, Cornelia C. Denison, spent the rest of their lives in Grand Rapids.
Their son, Arthur Carter Denison, was born in Grand Rapids on November 10, 1861. He received a LL.B degree from the University of Michigan in 1883 and soon became a prominent lawyer in Grand Rapids. In 1911 he was appointed United States circuit judge for the Sixth Circuit and also served as presiding judge of the Court of Appeals. He resigned his position in 1932 to re-enter law practice.
The Denison Family papers date from 1848 to 1907 and measure one linear foot. The papers document the day to day activities in a segment of the lives of Julius and Cornelia Denison and their son Arthur.
The papers of Julius Coe Denison date from 1848 to 1878 and include correspondence, receipts, land deeds and other papers. The papers of Cornelia Denison (1885 to 1907) and Arthur Denison (1879 to 1889) are principally diaries which contain brief entries about their daily activities, lists of books they read, and lists of expenses. The early diaries of Arthur Denison document his activities at the University of Michigan.
Subjects:
Grand Rapids (Mich.).; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1881-1890.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1871-1880.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1881-1890.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1891-1900.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1901-1910.; Michigan--Social life and customs--19th century.; Michigan--Social life and customs--20th century.; Women--Michigan--Grand Rapids.
Contributors:
Denison, Arthur Carter, b. 1861.; Denison, Cornelia Carter.; Denison, Julius Coe.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.
- Julius Coe Denison (husband of Cornelia)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - 1848-1869 (scattered dates) (Box 1)
  - 1871-1874 (Box 1)
  - 1876-1878 (Box 1)
  - Receipts and Bills, 1874-1877 (Box 1)
  - Land Deeds and Contracts, 1848-1873 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1850-1873 (scattered dates) (Box 1)
- Cornelia Carter Denison (wife of Julius)
  - Diaries, 1886-1890 and 1897-1907, 16 volumes (Box 1)
  - Letter, 1885 (Box 1)
- Arthur Carter Denison (son of Julius and Cornelia)
  - Diaries, 1879-1889, 11 volumes (Box 1)
  - Letter, 1879, and biographical material (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1905-1910 (Box 1)